# ADAM VIGEANT

UX DESIGNER I DESIGN THINKER



# CONTACT

603-321-3749



AdamVigeantUX@gmail.com



AVigeant.com



linkedin.com/in/adam-vigeant/

# **UX SKILLS**

- Design Thinking
- User-Centered Design
- UI & Visual Design
- Wireframes & Prototyping
- User Experience Research
- Design Personas
- User Flows
- Journey Maps
- Information Architecture
- Usability Testing
- Interaction Design

# TOOLS

- Adobe CC (Creative Cloud)
- Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe XD
- Axure
- Balsamiq
- Figma
- InVision
- Sketch
- HTML/CSS
- Javascript

## PROFILE

UX designer with a passion to solve challenging problems. A capable and empathetic mediator between client, business, and development teams, with strong problemsolving abilities rooted in Design Thinking.

With deep knowledge of UX/UI tools and methods, and 10+ years experience in visual design—strong communication skills, high level of adaptability, and growth mindset make Adam a valuable contributor to any team.

## EXPERIENCE

## **UX & VISUAL DESIGN CONTRACTOR**

#### AV Design | 2011-Present

- Collaborated with various clients to implement design solutions that meet specific needs and vision.
- Implemented effective communication, timemanagement, and organizational strategy to ensure high-quality work.
- Protected client interest by preserving brand identity, while respecting time and financial parameters.
- Improved effectiveness through researching industry tools, techniques, and best practices to design for maximum impact.
- Designed over 10 unique brand identities, in addition to numerous web, graphic, and informational deliverables.

#### **DESIGN CONSULTANT**

## Powell Prints | 2015-2021

- Mediated between management, sales, product production, customer service, and clients to produce effective design solutions.
- Utilized Design Thinking to develop creative solutions to address business and client needs.
- Advised management and production teams on current design trends and recommended viable improvements.
- Facilitated client meetings to identify needs, build relational equity, and establish project parameters.
- Curated over 300 visual designs for various clients, including Ohio State University and Columbus Zoo.

# **EDUCATION**

Certification in UX Design & Frontend Development

CareerFoundry | 2020-2021

#### Bachelor of Science in Media Design

Indiana Wesleyan University | 2009-2013